[
    {
        "numb": 1,
        "question": "Which of the following statements about organizational behaviour is (OB) false?",
        "answer": " OB is relevant only in employment situations",
        "options": [
            " OB is relevant only in employment situations",
            "OB can shed light on the interactions among family members",
            "OB can be used in community settings like children's daycare more effectively",
            "OB can be applied to any organization in order to make it run more effectively"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 2,
        "question": "Which of the following situations would likely receive the least benefit from studying organizational behaviour (OB) techniques?",
        "answer": "pre-teen paper routes",
        "options": [
            "post-secondary education student study groups",
            "voluntary community groups",
            "pre-teen paper routes",
            "religious organizations"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 3,
        "question": "A field of study that investigates the impact of individuals, groups, and structure on behaviour within organization is known as:",
        "answer": "organizational behaviour",
        "options": [
            "psychology",
            "organizational behaviour",
            "social psychology",
            "anthropology"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 4,
        "question": "A conscious coordinated social unit composed of a group of people that function on a relatively continuous basic to achieve a common set of goals is known as a(n)",
        "answer": "organization",
        "options": [
            "work group",
            " team",
            "organization",
            "task force"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 5,
        "question": "Which of the following topics is generally considered to be outside the field of OB?",
        "answer": "therapy",
        "options": [
            "therapy",
            "employment turnover",
            "job satisfaction",
            "absenteeism"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 6,
        "question": "What are the three rules about behvaviour that attribution theory relies on?",
        "answer": "consistency, consensus, and distinctiveness",
        "options": [
            "distinctiveness, resemblance, and consistency",
            "consistency, consensus, and distinctiveness",
            "context, consensus, and distinctiveness",
            "resemblance, consensus, and consistency"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 7,
        "question": "are defined as people who oversee the activities of others and who are responsible for attaining goals in organizations",
        "answer": "Managers",
        "options": [
            "Apprentices",
            "Interns",
            "Secretaries",
            "Managers"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 8,
        "question": "The instructions in 68000 can deal with operands of three different sizes",
        "answer": "True",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 9,
        "question": "As the instructions can deal with variable size operands we use ____________ to resolve this.",
        "answer": "Size indicator mnemonic",
        "options": [
            "None of the mentioned",
            "Size indicator mnemonic",
            "Special assemblers",
            "Delimiter"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 10,
        "question": "The starting address is denoted using _________ directive",
        "answer": "ORG",
        "options": [
            "ORG",
            "ORIGIN",
            "EQU",
            "PLACE"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 11,
        "question": "The constant can be declared using ___________ directive.",
        "answer": "DC",
        "options": [
            "CONS",
            "PLACE",
            "DC",
            "DATAWORD"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 12,
        "question": "To allocate a block of memory we use ___________ directive",
        "answer": "DS",
        "options": [
            "PLACE",
            "RESERVE",
            "DATAWORD",
            "DS"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 13,
        "question": "The Branch instruction in 68000 provides how many types of offsets?",
        "answer": "2",
        "options": [
            "3",
            "2",
            "1",
            "0"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 14,
        "question": "What part of the CPU is being described",
        "answer": "ALU",
        "options": [
            "ALU",
            "Cache",
            "Control Unit",
            "Memory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 15,
        "question": "The PC register holds what?",
        "answer": "The address for the next instruction",
        "options": [
            "The accumulated memory location",
            "The instruction for the next instruction",
            "The data for the next instruction",
            "The address for the next instruction"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 16,
        "question": "Which of these is not a system utility program?",
        "answer": "A graphics card driver",
        "options": [
            "Memory and CPU monitor",
            "A graphics card driver",
            "Defragmentation software",
            "Diagnostic software in case of computer crash"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 17,
        "question": "Re-organises the files by putting the related files next to each other",
        "answer": "Defragmentation",
        "options": [
            "Compression",
            "Encryption",
            "Auto-Update",
            "Defragmentation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 18,
        "question": "What is the purpose of Utility Software?",
        "answer": "all the above",
        "options": [
            "To keep the computer organised",
            "To ensure it has up to date software",
            "To ensure the system runs efficiently",
            "all the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 19,
        "question": "Translates low level assembly language mnemonic into machine code",
        "answer": "Assembler",
        "options": [
            "Interpreter",
            "Compiler",
            "Assembler",
            "Executable"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 20,
        "question": "Which of the following statements about libraries is not true?",
        "answer": "Code generated that includes libraries, cannot be converted to stand alone code",
        "options": [
            "An advantage of libraries is that they consist of code that has already been checked and compiled",
            "Code generated that includes libraries, cannot be converted to stand alone code",
            "Programmers can write their own libraries",
            "Libraries could include functions for generating random numbers or performing mathematical calculations"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 21,
        "question": "What characteristics of RAM makes it not suitable for permanent memory?",
        "answer": "Volatile in nature",
        "options": [
            "Unreliable",
            "Volatile in nature",
            "To slow",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 22,
        "question": "Computers use addressing mode technique for:",
        "answer": "All of the above",
        "options": [
            "To reduce numbers of bits in the field of instruction",
            "Specifying rules for modifying or interpreting address field of the instruction",
            "Giving programming versatility  to the user by providing facilities by providing facilities as pointers to memory computer for loop control",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 23,
        "question": "Which of the following is the lowest in memory hierarchy?",
        "answer": "Secondary memory",
        "options": [
            "Cache memory",
            "Register",
            "RAM",
            "Secondary memory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 24,
        "question": "A group of bits that tell the computer to perform a specific operation is known as:",
        "answer": "Instruction code",
        "options": [
            "Accumulator",
            "Register",
            "Micro operation",
            "Instruction code"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 25,
        "question": "",
        "answer": "Data bus",
        "options": [
            "I/O bus",
            "Address bus",
            "Data bus",
            "Control lines"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 26,
        "question": "Data input command is just the opposite of a:",
        "answer": "Data output",
        "options": [
            "Data output",
            "Data channel",
            "Test command",
            "Control command"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 27,
        "question": "A binary digit is called:",
        "answer": "Register",
        "options": [
            "Bit",
            "Byte",
            "Register",
            "Character"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 28,
        "question": "The operation executed in data and stored in the register is called :",
        "answer": "Micro operation",
        "options": [
            "byte operation",
            "Bit operation",
            "Micro operation",
            "Macro operation"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 29,
        "question": "Which of the following is the main memory?",
        "answer": "Cache memory",
        "options": [
            "Cache memory",
            "Auxiliary memory",
            "Secondary memory ",
            "Virtual memory"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 30,
        "question": "The most common addressing techniques used by CPU is:",
        "answer": "All of the above ",
        "options": [
            "Immediate addressing techniques",
            "Indirect addressing techniques",
            "Direct addressing techniques",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    }
]